

Andrei Vasiloi

Nationality: Romanian

(+40) 766246844

Date of birth: 16/04/1990

Gender: Male

Email address: andrei_vasiloi@yahoo.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrei-vasiloi/

• Address: Brasov, Str. Apollo, Nr. 5, Brasov (Romania)

ABOUT ME

Before learning web technologies like React & Redux, my IT experience started when I participated in the courses organized by the Cisco company. I started this course with IT essentials, continued with CCNA for networking. I managed to finish all the four modules of the CCNA course, however, I was not so much attracted to this domain. Approximately two years ago I tried to see if programming interests me more and that's how I started to learn HTML and CSS. When I realized that I enjoy it I continued with JavaScript. That's how I become very motivated and I started to learn by myself every day. Parallelly I managed to qualify for an internship offered by Pentalog for React technology. After this period I have started to create my own application, which is a tool for small businesses where you can have clear evidence of schedules, inventory of products, their expiration date, and so on. I had great satisfaction in creating this application and each characteristic of it. It made me more confident in achieving my goals. For the good function of the application, I have used technologies such as React, JavaScript, Redux, and Firestore.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Self-employed [02/2021 - 03/2021]

Country: Romania

My recent project is a website for a fictional restaurant. At this app, I have used only HTML, CSS, SASS, and Bootstrap. I wanted to build this page to enhance my CSS skills.

GitHub link - https://github.com/AndreiVasiloi/kronstadtFood.git

Website link - https://kronstadtfood.netlify.app/

React Developer

Self-employed [10/2020 - 12/2020]

Country: Romania

I have studied various Udemy courses to develop my skills to be a Front End Developer. With the

accumulated knowledge, I started to build my own application. My goal was to make an app that helps

small businesses. In the beginning, I wanted to have only two sections for the inventory and

appointments. After I have managed to finish these sections, I realized that I can add more. So, I have

started to add new things to increase the complexity of my app.

GitHub link - https://github.com/AndreiVasiloi/ManagementApp

Website link - https://managementapp-d440e.firebaseapp.com/

Video Presentation link - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J4OHbObfZJs

CNC Operator

S.C.Premium Aerotec S.R.L. [03/2017 - Current]

City: Brasov

Country: Romania

- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and a fast-paced atmosphere.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to ensure projects were completed on time.
- Preparing everything is need to make the aircraft's parts conformable with the tehnic design.
- Modify the cutting program to make the achievement of parts more efficient.

CNC Operator

S.C. Schaeffler S.R.L. [06/2016 – 03/2017]

City: Brasov

Country: Romania

- Maintained tight tolerances with design specifications.
- Properly loaded and unloaded materials in and out of machines.
- Moved finished work to correct staging area for disposition.
- Manually set up machinery and equipment.
- Measured completed pieces to identify product irregularities and specifications non-conformance; adjusting machines to correct issues.

Receptionist

S.C. Colina S.R.L. [10/2010 – 06/2016]

City: Brasov

- Kept reception area clean and neat to give visitors a positive first impression.
- Answered telephone calls to field inquiries from clients, vendors, and various other callers seeking information.
- Resolved customer problems and complaints.
- Checked-in visitors, distributed visitor badges, and managed logbooks to comply with security initiatives.
- Corresponded with clients through email, telephone, or postal mail.
- Coordinated travel accommodations for staff and out-of-town visitors, including vouchers, agendas, and transportation.
- Routed incoming mail and messages to relevant personnel without delay.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Certificate of participation

Udemy [01/2019 - 02/2021]

Address: Remote

Udemy courses that I have followed:

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp

Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations, and More!

The Complete JavaScript Course 2021: From Zero to Expert!

React - The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)

Build an app with React, Redux, and Firestore from scratch

Certificate of Participation - React

Pentalog - Pentastagiu [11/2018 – 03/2019]

Address: Brasov (Romania)

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies : *Software and applications development and analysis*

The course included the basics of React. We had a remote session every week with two instructors that explained new terms every time.

It was a good opportunity for me to learn new things and meet new people that had the same passion as me.

Certificate of Participation

TechAdviser [10/2013 - 05/2015]

Address: Brasov (Romania)

- Cisco IT Essentials
- Cisco CCNA Routing & Switching (1-4)

IT Essentials taught me the basics of how computers work, and how to maintain them.

After this journey, I have started to learn about networking. This course was more complex and taught me all about computer networks. After each finished module, I had to take a theoretical and practical test to go to the next module. It was not an easy task, but with hard work, I managed to finish all the four CCNA (Routing & Switching) modules.

Bachelor's Degree Economist - Management

Spiru Haret University Brasov [2010 – 2013]

Address: Brasov (Romania)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

Romanian

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

DIGITAL SKILLS

Web Development: HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript / CSS SAAS SCSS / Firebase (Functions, Auth, Firestore, Storage) / Firestore / BOOTSTRAP 3/4 / GIT (GitHub) / JSON / Microsoft Office / Visual Studio / Visual Studio Code / MaterialUI / React Hooks React Bootstrap React Router React Hooks / Redux

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B